Previously on Elementary...
I've done something new
to anger you.
You didn't mention
you were the target
of a failed
assassination attempt
which left a woman
named Sabine dead.
I was right.
Two years ago, he thought
I was behind his near-murder.
And now?
According to him,
I am a former suspect
and I am not at the center
of an elaborate revenge plot.
Sabine and I were...
very close.
The would-be assassin
has been dealt with.
Well, you're lying,
so I'll just have to investigate
the matter myself.
세인트 마틴, 퀘백
헉, 괜찮아, 프로스티
Hey, it's okay, Frosty.
Hi, I'm so sorry
to bother you,
갑자기 찾아와서 미안해요
차가 길에서 멈춘데다 폰도 꺼졌어요
but my car broke down up
the road and my phone died.
Oh, Mon Dieu. Of all the nights.
I know.
오, 저런, 하필이면 밤에
그러니까요, 제가 바보같았어요
Feel like an idiot. Do you think
I could use your phone
친구한테 데리러 오라고 할건데
전화를 빌려주실 수 있을까요?
to call my friend
to come and pick me up?
Uh...
어
그럼요. 들어오세요
Of course. Come in.
고마워요. 생명의 은인이에요
Thank you.
You're a lifesaver.
Oh.
오
You're so cute.
정말 귀엽네
오, 얘는 프로스티예요
Oh, this is Frosty.
I'm Soleil.
I'm, uh,
전 솔레일이에요
전 니콜레뜨예요
I'm Nicolette.
전화는 서재에 있어요
Uh, here.
The phone is in the study.
Uh, I'm not interrupting
anything, am I?
제가 방해를 한 건 아니죠?
"해양 괴물" 보고 있었어요
(The Creature from the Black Lagoon)
Only The Creature
from the Black Lagoon.
My favorite show
got preempted by hockey.
하키보다 더 좋아하는 영화죠
Uh, you want
a cup of tea?
차 한잔 드릴까요?
Oh. That's so nice, thank you.
오. 좋아요. 고마워요
Yeah.
나오지 말아요
Keep warm!
정말 고마웠어요
Thanks so much.
안녕
Bye!
?Nicolette??
니콜레뜨?
Everyone within
100 miles of Montreal
몬트리올에서 100마일 이내에 사는
사람들이 모두 프랑스 이름이잖아요
has a sexy French name.
아니면 의심스러웠을걸요
Would've been suspicious
if I didn't.
What'd you find?
뭐 찾았어요?
솔레일은 순종적인 딸이었어요
Soleil is a dutiful daughter.
어머니의 편지, 유품, 다른
기념품들을 간직하고 있었어요
She's kept her mother's letters,
her will
and some other mementos.
답이 안에 있길 바라요
Hopefully,
the answers lie within.
없다면, 사비나 라울을 강령술로
불러야할지도 몰라요
If not, I shall resort
to a s챕ance
to interrogate
Sabine Raoult.
아버님의 여친이 계획한 일인지
You can't be that sure
확신할 수 없군요
that your father's girlfriend
set him up.
She died in the attack.
당시 공격으로 사망했어요
Well, perhaps that's
a convenient outcome
범죄를 모의한 사람 누구에게나
유리한 결과죠
for whoever
commissioned the crime.
????
♪ Elementary 4x14 ♪
Who Is That Masked Man
Original Air Date on February 25, 2016
??Elementary 4x14 ??/font>
Who Is That Masked Man
Original Air Date on February 25, 2016
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
실례합니다
Excuse me, excuse me.
고마워요, 고마워요
Thank you, sorry. Thank you.
구경꾼들이 많네
That's quite an audience today.
파파라치가 없는 게 아니라면
If it wasn't for
the lack of paparazzi,
리얼리티 TV 스타가
파헤쳐진 줄 알았겠어요
I'd assume a reality TV
star got vivisected.
3명의 중국계 조폭이 총살됐어
Three Chinese gangsters
got shotgunned.
별로 안 땡겨요
So less fun.
이 동네는 예민해졌어
These folks are nervous.
조폭 전쟁의 시작일까봐 걱정하고 있지
They're worried this could be
the beginning of a gang war.
경감님 생각은요?
What do you think?
그의 생각을 알면
I'd have a better idea
더 좋은 생각이 나겠지
if I knew what
he was thinking.
멩 주, 저쪽에 모자쓴 사람이야
That's Meng Zhou,
in the hat over there.
He's the head of
the Snake Eye Boys.
'사안회(the Snake Eye Boys) 두목이지
시내에서 2번째로 큰 삼합회야
Second largest
Triad in the city.
저기 쓰러져 있는 애들이 부하들이야
It's his guys
on the ground in there.
멩씨를 노리는 사람이 누구죠?
And who is Mr. Meng
likely to blame?
귀산(Ghost Mountain)
Ghost Mountain.
또다른 삼합회인데 신생조직이지
Another Triad, just
came to the States.
콜럼버스 파크 근처 일대가 주무대야
They control a few blocks
near Columbus Park.
Beat cops say there's
been some friction.
순경 말로는 마찰이 있었다는군
We were afraid of
something like this.
이런 일을 우려했었어
오락실은 피해자 3명의 공동소유였어
The arcade is co-owned
by the three victims.
전과 기록은 화려해
Their rap sheets
are all over the map.
When they weren't
scamming credit cards
신용카드나 보험회사
사기를 치지 않을 때는
and insurance companies,
they were running
불법 약물을 팔고
보호비를 뜯으러다녔지
illegal drugs
and protection rackets.
Sound like big earners.
돈 많이 벌었겠네요
맞아. 그래서 보복은 빠르고
무자비하게 일어날지도 몰라
Yeah. That's why
retribution will probably be
fast and bloody.
가능한 빨리 범인을 체포해야해
We need to make a collar
on this ASAP,
이 동네 전체가 폭파될 수도 있어
or this whole neighborhood
could blow up.
3개의 혈흔, 2명의 피해자, 1개의 칼을 봤어요
So I count three blood spatters,
two victims, one knife.
마지막 피해자가 잭나이프를 꺼냈어
The last guy managed
to get his switchblade out.
범인에게 잡히기 전에
We think he got winged,
made it around the corner
칼을 휘두르며 구석으로 갔을거야
before the killer
caught up with him.
목격자는 없겠죠?
I take it there were
no witnesses?
조사해서 총성을 들은 사람들,
Uh, we canvassed, talked
to a few people who heard shots,
창문 밖을 본 사람들과
얘기를 했는데
looked out
their windows.
한 커플은 조깅하는 사람을 봤고
One couple
saw a jogger.
다른 사람은 총격지에서
급하게 뛰어가는
Someone else saw
a little old woman
작은 할머니를
봤다는군, 그게 다야
hightailing it away
from the gunfire. That's it.
Well, there are
no surveillance cameras.
보안카메라가 없네요
놀랍지는 않아요
That's not surprising,
여기가 사용된 목적을 보면요
considering what this
place was used for.
Is this MDMA?
MDMA죠?
$25,000 어치야
That's $25,000 worth.
They kept their stash
in a safe behind the counter.
카운터 뒤 금고에 보관해뒀어
So the killer
couldn't break the lock?
그럼 범인이 자물쇠를
열지는 않았을까요?
손대지도 않았어
I don't think he touched it.
목적이 뭐였든, 강도는 아니야
Whatever this was,
it wasn't a robbery.
배신일 가능성을 생각해봐야해요
Uh, I think it
might have been a betrayal.
복도에서의 습격이죠
Ambush by an ally.
왜 그런 말을 하지?
What makes you say that?
There's sodium bicarbonate here,
여기 중탄산나트륨이
lying in a pool
마른 가래 웅덩이에 있었어요
of dried expectoration.
The killer put a fizzy
pain reliever in his mouth
범인은 진통제를 입에 넣어
가짜 경련을 했어요
to fake a seizure.
피해자들의 도움을 유인하기 위해서
To lure the victims to his aid.
피해자들이 긴장을 풀자
범인은 총격을 가했어요
They opened up, he opened fire.
외부인에게 속았을 가능성은 없을까요?
They couldn't have been
fooled by a stranger?
This man put a 9 and a 1 in his
phone just before he was shot.
이 사람은 총에 맞기 전
폰에 91을 찍었어요
개인적으로 도와야할 사람이 아니었다면
I don't think he would've
brought the police
불법 약물이 널린 곳에 경찰과
and the paramedics
to his drug-slinging pit
구급대원을 불렀을리가 없어요
if it wasn't for someone
he personally cared for.
So the trigger man
그럼 총격범은 피해자들과
같은 '사안회'일 것이다
was probably a Snake Eye,
same as the victims.
변절하고 지금은 '귀산'과
일하고 있다는 거죠
So he switched
allegiances
and now he's working
with Ghost Mountain?
시험하기 힘든 가설이야
Hard theory to test.
내가 말했듯이,
귀산은 신흥조직이야
Like I said,
Ghost Mountain's new.
우린 친분이 있는 사람이 없어
We don't have anyone plugged
into their drama.
There are other ways
to ascertain
귀산이 상대 조직에
이중첩자를 심어놨는지
whether Ghost Mountain has
cultivated a double agent
알아낼 방법은 있어요
in their enemy's organization.
????
미스터 시, 저희는 NYPD 자문탐정입니다
Mr. Xi, we are consultants
with the NYPD.
시간 있어요?
Do you have a minute?
Who are you looking for?
누굴 찾아 왔어요?
당신이오. 시하이칭
You.
Xi Hai Ching.
귀산 삼합회의 "48"이죠
The so-called ??8??
of the Ghost Mountain Triad.
Everyone on this block
pays you protection, Mr. Xi,
이 블록의 모든 사람들이
보호비를 내고 있죠
거부할 엄두도 못내고
there's no sense denying it.
부정하겠어요
I do deny it.
'시'라는 사람은 없어요
There's no one
here named Xi.
The department has been keeping
an eye on you since June.
경찰은 6월부터 당신을 지켜봤어요
We may not have all the
information we want about you,
당신에 대한 모든 정보를 얻지 못했지만
당신 이름은 잘 알아요
but we do know
your name.
Three members of
the Snake Eye Boys
어제 오락실에서 사안회
멤버 3명이 급습을 당했어요
were ambushed at
an arcade last night.
이중배신을 한 그들의 동료에게
돈을 줬다는 의심이 들어요
We suspect you paid one of their
fellows to double-cross them.
I am not leader
of Ghost Mountain.
난 귀산의 두목이 아니오
귀산은 들어본 적도 없어요
I never hear of Ghost Mountain.
내 자신을 대변할 뿐이
I only speak for myself.
Well, you'd be
wise to do so,
그렇게 행동해야 현명하겠죠
'cause as we see it,
우리가 알기로는
모트 스트리트에서 대학살로 당신보다
no one stood to benefit more
더 이득을 보는 사람은 없으니까요
from the carnage
at Mott Street than you.
직접 처리하는 편이라고 알고 있어요
We know from your file
you're very hands-on.
어젯밤 일어난 일도 지켜봤죠?
Maybe you watched the whole
thing go down last night?
어젯밤에는 여자친구와 함께 있었어요
I was with a woman friend
last night.
남편이 시외에 있어서
Her husband is out of town.
She's married,
유부녀라서
알리바이를 증언해주지 않겠군요
so she won't be able
to back up your story.
그럴 필요 없어요
She won't have to.
병원에서 전화를 받았지
She got a call from hospital.
Her nephew.
애인의 조카로부터
구타당하고 돈도 뺐겼다더군
He was beaten and mugged.
우린 병원에 같이 있었어요
We went there to be with him.
어느 병원이죠?
Which one?
St. Bede's. Go there.
성 베다 병원이오. 가보시오
날 믿지 못한다면 가서 물어봐요
Ask them
if you don't believe me.
This is a dangerous
neighborhood.
여긴 위험한 동네지
경찰이 우릴 지켜주지 못해
The police cannot keep us safe.
사람들이 보호비를 내야한다면
If people have
to pay for protection,
maybe you should blame yourself.
경찰들 자신을 비난해야겠지
I'll check his alibi
휴대폰 내역을 조사할동안
난 알리바이를 확인할게요
while you comb
through his cell phone.
저 리프트 봤어요?
You saw that lift?
복제하려고 지웠잖아요?
You swapped it out
for a duplicate, right?
말웨어와 닳은 배터리
With malware and a dead battery.
통화 기록을 살펴보고
귀산 가족도도 확인하려면
Should give me enough time
to review his call history,
flesh out the Ghost Mountain
family tree.
시간을 충분히 줘야해요
운이 좋으면 사안회 쪽에서
With any luck, I should
find the Snake Eye mole
위험을 감지하고 일회용폰을
before he has time
to sound the alarm
모두 없애기 전에 찾아야해요
and they all swap out
their burners.
Mmm.
지구 건너편에서 돌아오신 줄 몰랐어요
Wasn't aware you were back
on this side of the globe.
좋아하지 않아도 일 때문에
My business brings me
back to this city
자주 이 도시로 오게 된다
more often than I'd like.
좋아하지 않아도 아들의 행동 때문에
My son's behavior
brings me back
to this brownstone
more often than I'd like.
이 집에 자주 오게 되는구나
이번에는 제가 심기를 상하게 했나요?
How have I offended now?
왜 사비나를 조사하고 있지?
Why are you looking into Sabine?
What gave you the idea I am?
왜 그렇게 생각하셨어요?
I was informed
by the woman you robbed.
네가 도둑질을 한 여자로부터 들었다
Did you really think
that Soleil and I
솔레일과 내가 연락을 안한다고 생각했니?
would not still
be in contact?
바로 그렇게 추측했었어요
That's precisely
what I'd assumed.
그 사건 후
After the attack,
솔레일은 어머니의 죽음으로
날 비난했어야했어
she could've blamed me
for her mother's death.
대신 내 회복을 위해 기도했지
Instead, she prayed
for my recovery.
I owe her answers,
더이상 슬프지 않도록
해결도 못해줬는데
not more grief, so you can
imagine my frustration
미인이지만 불운했던 동양계 여성운전자가
집에 방문했던 날과 같은날 밤에
when I heard that
her home had been violated
집이 털렸다는 얘기를 듣고
the same night
as she was visited
얼마나 당황스러웠는지 상상이 되겠니
by a beautiful
but hapless Asian motorist.
Watson and I did not
travel to Quebec on a lark.
왓슨과 난 재미삼아 퀘벡으로
가지는 않았어
그럼 왜 갔지?
Then why did you go?
There's good reason to believe
사비나가 아버지의
목숨을 노린 일당이라고
that Sabine was a party
to the attempt on your life.
믿을만한 이유가 있었어요
Oh, Sherlock...
오, 셜록
아마 사비나의 참여를 자신도 몰랐거나
Perhaps her participation
was unwitting,
아마 사비나에 대해 잘못 알고 계셨겠죠
perhaps you're just wrong
about her character.
어느 쪽이든
Either way,
총격범은
the shooter
언제 어디서 일을 해야할지
was far too well-prepared
지나치게 잘 알고 있었어요
to strike when and where he did.
He rented a room
above the plaza,
광장 위에 방을 빌리고
교통 카메라를 고장내고,
탈출 경로를 숙지하고
disabled a traffic camera,
mapped his escape route...
All of those facts
이 모든 사실은
사비나가 그날 저녁에
레스토랑을 골랐다는
are completely at odds
with your assertion
아버지의 주장과
완벽하게 불일치합니다
that Sabine chose the restaurant
on the spur of the moment
that evening.
불가능해
It's impossible.
"불가능하다"와 "상상하기
힘들다"는 전혀 다릅니다
There is a vast gulf
between ?impossible??
and ?impossible to imagine.??
아니
No.
전부 재검토해라
You've got everything backwards.
I am to blame for
what happened to her.
사비나에게 일어난 일로
비난받을 사람은 나다
우리가 만나지 않았다면
오늘까지 살아있었을거야
If we had never met,
she would still be alive today.
Someone I loved was annihilated
because of me.
내가 사랑했던 사람이
나 때문에 죽었어
Well, there's
an overdue sentiment.
지나치게 감상적이군요
To invoke your mother now...
네 어머니도 그랬다
You haven't changed.
넌 변하지 않았구나
사비나 조사를 중단하지 않을 겁니다
I'm not going to stop
looking into Sabine.
사비나가 열쇠예요
She is the key.
Marcus. Hi.
마커스, 안녕
왔어요
Hey.
-설탕 2개
-요청한 파일이에요
Two sugars.
The file you asked for.
오는 길에 14번서에 들렸어요
I swung by the 14th
on my way in.
Ugh...
이번 사건은 더 좋게 끝날 거예요
You're getting the better
end of this deal.
시 하이칭은 어젯밤 행방에
대해 거짓말을 했군요
So Xi Hai Ching was lying
about where he was last night.
아뇨, 하지만 강도 사건이 3건의
No, but I think the assault
he told you about
살인사건과 관련이 있다고 생각해요
might be connected
to the three homicides.
Kevin Chang.
케빈 창
So he's the nephew
of Xi's mistress?
시의 애인의 조카가 맞아요?
Mm-hmm.
오락실에서 2블럭 거리에서 다쳤나봐요
Well, it looks like
he got jumped
just two blocks from the arcade.
네, 총격 5분후였어요
Yeah, about five minutes after
the shots were fired there.
험한 동네긴 하지만
I get that it's a rough
neighborhood,
우연은 아니겠죠?
but that's a serious
coincidence, no?
Keep flipping.
계속 넘겨봐요
Someone hit him
with a blunt object.
둔기로 때렸다
Well, that looks
like it could be
엽총의 개머리판으로
맞은 것 같지 않아요?
from the stock of a shotgun,
couldn't it?
내 생각도 같았어요
That's what I thought.
크기도 맞아요
It's about the right size.
단순 강도사건이 아니었을 거예요
So maybe this wasn't
a mugging after all.
케빈은 잘못된 시간에
잘못된 장소에 있다가
Kevin was in the wrong
place at the wrong time,
봐선 안될 걸 봤던거죠
saw something he
shouldn't have.
범인은 삼합회에 덮어씌우려고 했고
The shooter spent all his ammo
blasting the Triad
케빈을 쫓아가서 죽을
정도로 때려야했어요
and had to chase Kevin down
and tried to beat him to death.
일을 거의 끝낸 것 같아요
Looks like he almost
finished the job.
Last notes say that the doctors
had to put him in a coma
마지막 장에 뇌의 부종이 가라앉을 때까지
의사가 혼수상태를 유지시킬
거라고 적혀있어요
until the swelling
in his brain subsides.
케빈이 깨어나면 인상착의를
I doubt Kevin will
be able to give us
설명해줄 수 있을지 의심스러워요
much of a description
if he wakes up.
하지만 케빈을 발견한 사람과는
얘기할 수 있어요
But we can talk
to the people who found him.
현장에서 도망치는 범인을
봤을 수도 있어요
Maybe they saw the perp
fleeing the scene.
셜록에게 연락할게요
I'll call Sherlock.
Yeah, so I was
the third person
네, 그래서 내가 가서 모든 걸
지켜본 3번째 사람이었어요
to come along
and see the whole mess.
먼저 그를 발견한 사람들은
노숙자 2명이었어요
People who found him were
these two homeless guys.
폰도 없었고,
꽤 취해있었죠
They, uh, didn't have a phone
and they were pretty drunk.
저쪽 블록에서 걸어가다가
I was walking along
the block there,
도와달라는 소리를 듣고
여기로 왔었어요
and I heard him yell for help,
so I came on over.
뭘 봤죠?
What did you see?
Kevin.
케빈
그 사람 이름 맞죠?
That's his name, right?
네, 피범벅이 되어 있었어요
Yeah, he was just
covered in blood.
누구한테 세게 맞았는지
횡설수설하면서
Somebody really bashed him,
and he's babbling and...
-그때는 의식이 있었어요?
-그런 편이죠
Wait, he was still conscious?
Kind of.
정신이 없어보이긴 했어요
He wasn't making much sense.
할머니가 그랬다고 했거든요
Said an old lady did it.
네?
What?
오락실 근처에서 살던 사람이
Someone who lives
above the arcade said
어젯밤 현장에서 할머니가
they saw an old
woman hurrying away
급히 뛰어가는 걸 봤다고 했어요
from the scene of the
shooting last night.
할머니가 3명의 중국계
조폭을 총으로 쏘고
You think some little
old lady gunned down
three Chinese gangsters
케빈 창의 머리를 엽총으로
때렸다고 생각해요?
and then caved Kevin Chang's
skull in with a shotgun?
동일 인물에 의한 사건이라면
왓슨이 맞아요
Watson is correct
that the crimes were committed
by the same person.
하지만 그 사람은 할머니가 아니에요
But I don't think that person
was an elderly woman.
Might have looked like
an elderly woman, though.
할머니처럼 보이도록 변장했겠지만
앉아요
Have a seat.
뭡니까?
What is this?
난 이 사람과 같은 방에 있지 않겠소
I will not be in the same
room with this man.
두 사람 모두 가게 주인일
뿐이라고 강하게 주장했으니
Since you both have
sworn up and down
that you're just
simple shopkeeps,
잠깐 대화를 나눠도
문제 없겠죠, 안 그렇습니까?
I don't see the harm in
a little conversation. Do you?
We thought you
should know
우린 두 조직이 전쟁을 하지
말아야한다고 생각했어요
that your gangs don't need
to go to war after all.
미스터 멩, 오락실 사건은 미스터 시의 조직이
Mr. Meng, we're almost positive
Mr. Xi's organization
벌인 일이 아니라고 거의 확신합니다
had nothing to do
with the arcade killings.
?Almost.??
거의?
Yeah, it depends
on whether or not
네, 귀산이나 사안회에 "백인"이
있는지 없는지에 따라서요
there's any bak gwei in Ghost
Mountain or the Snake Eye Boys.
백인? 삼합회에?
A white man? In a Triad?
-그렇습니다
-살인 흉기를 찾았어요
- That's what we thought.
- We found the murder weapon.
오락실에서 2블록 떨어진
곳에서 케빈 창이라는
It was used to beat a man
named Kevin Chang senseless
남자를 무자비하게
때릴 때 사용됐어요
just two blocks
from the arcade.
애인의 조카 맞죠?
That's your girlfriend's
nephew, right?
Well, uh, that's a
coincidence. Sort of.
우연의 일치입니다
케빈은, 아마 아시겠지만,
노상강도로 용의자였어요
Kevin, as you probably know,
is a suspected mugger himself.
적어도 몇건의 사건에 연루됐었죠
Or at least he's a person
of interest in a few open cases.
어젯밤 도망치는 범인을 털려던
Looks like last night
he made the mistake
시도가 실수였던 것으로 보입니다
of trying to rob
a killer on the run.
The beating he ended up
taking attracted attention,
구타로 인해 관심을 끌게 됐고
범인은 자신의 물건들을 버리기로 결심해요
so the shooter decided
to... ditch his stuff.
We found this mask
hidden in the same spot.
같은 곳에서 버려진 마스크를 발견했어요
실리콘과 장의사의
접합제로 만들어졌어요
It's made of silicone
and mortician's putty.
일반적으로 '접합제'는 시체의
상처를 가리는데 사용되지만
Usually the putty is used to
cover injuries on dead bodies,
가면을 잘 만들기 위해 사용될 수도 있죠
but obviously it can be utilized
in mask-making as well.
뒷면에 코카시안의 갈색
눈썹이 붙어 있었어요
There were several brown
Caucasian eyebrow hairs
stuck to the back.
오락실에서 발견한 씹어먹는 알약
껍질에서 발견된 DNA와 일치했어요
The hairs are
a preliminary DNA match
for a half-chewed seltzer tablet
that we found at the arcade.
경감, 그래서 무슨 말을 하는 겁니까?
Captain, just what
are you saying?
백인 남성이 중국인 할머니
분장을 하고 가짜 경련을 했어요
We're saying
a white man made himself
look like an old Chinese woman
and faked a seizure.
그래서 부하들이 마음을 놓고
도와주려고 했어요
That's why your guys dropped
their guard and came to his aid.
그리고 총에 맞았죠
And were gunned down
for their trouble.
My condolences.
조의를 표합니다
알았어, 고마워
All right. Thank you.
모두들 벙커에서 나와도 되겠어
Sounds like everybody's come
out of their bunkers.
차이나타운 순경들이
귀산과 사안회 멤버들이
Patrol cops in Chinatown
saw Ghost Mountain
and Snake Eye members
out and about last night.
다시 돌아다니는 걸 봤대
범죄자들은 항상 거리로 돌아오죠
Always great to get criminals
back out on the street.
우리가 원하는대로야
이번에는
Well, it's what we want.
This time.
총성은 없어
No shots fired.
변장의 달인이 다시
일을 벌이지 않는다면
Looks like the peace
will hold,
unless the master of disguise
decides to strike again.
평화는 지속될거야
변장의 달인은 아니라고 봅니다
I assure you there's no such
thing as a master of disguise.
있다면, 나 자신이겠죠
If there was,
I'd be one myself.
당연히 그러시겠지
Of course
you would.
당신 비웃지만 난
학교에서 연극을 배웠어
You scoff, but I did
drama at school.
무대 분장도 익혔지
I mastered stage makeup.
보철과 가발이 꽤 잘어울리지만
I was quite adept
with prosthetics and wigs,
한계가 있다는 것도 잘 알아요
but I learned that
they have their limits.
혐오하는 라이벌의 모습으로
A plan to infiltrate
a dining club
다이닝 클럽에 들어가려다
처참하게 실패했지
in the guise of a loathed rival
was a spectacular failure.
You think maybe this adult
killer is somehow
당신이 어렸을 때보다 더 좋은
변장 실력을 가진
범인이라고 생각해요?
even more skilled
than you were as a child?
I doubt it.
그렇지 않아
범인이 형사로 변장했다고 해봐요
Let's say he was
to impersonate you.
Adopting your appearance
would not be enough.
당신의 모습을 채택하는 건 쉽지 않아요
걸음걸이, 억양, 최근의
냄새까지 흉내내야해요
He'd have to mimic your gait,
your vocal inflection,
your very scent.
최고의 분장술을 한
연기력이 최고인 배우조차도
I doubt even
the most skilled actor
with the most
sophisticated makeup
먼 지인들을 통과할 수 있을지 의문이군요
could pass for an imbecile's
distant acquaintance.
하지만, 네가 말했듯이,
범인은 오락실에
And yet, according to you, our
perp tricked three Triad members
3명의 조폭들을 속이고 들어갔어
into letting him
into their arcade.
밤에 지저분한 창문을 통해서 봤고
He was seen at night
through a dirty window
입에 거품을 물고 경련하는 척을 했었죠
whilst foaming at the mouth
and pretending to seize.
'바이 메이룽'으로 변장했기 때문에
가능한 조합이었어요
All of this contributed
to their ability
to pass for Bai May-Lung.
바이 메이룽이 누구죠?
And who is
Bai May-Lung?
The Snake Eye Boys
called Bai ?Grandmother.??
사안회에서는 바이를
할머니라고 불러요
죽은 남편이 삼합회 두목이었어요
Her deceased husband was
a Triad lieutenant.
He used his wife's hair salon
to launder money.
아내의 미용실을 돈세탁에 이용했죠
앨비언 교도소에서 3년형을 끝내고
She just finished
a three-year bid
6개월 전에 출소했어요
at Albion Correctional
six months ago.
세 피해자의 입장으로 보면
Revered by the three victims
for her service
극도로 의심하지 않는
이상, 완벽했어요
and unsuspecting in the extreme,
she's perfect.
인정하지
I'm sold.
둘이 가서 얘기를 해보지그래
Why don't you two go have a
chat with her, see if she has
변장했을만한 사람을 알지도 몰라
any idea who would have
wanted to impersonate her.
Respectfully, Mrs. Bai served
a prison sentence in her 70s
바이는 70대를 감옥에서 보내서
주에 협조적이지는 않을 겁니다
rather than cooperate
with the state.
뱃지 가진 사람과는 말하지 않을걸요
She won't talk to anyone
with a badge.
그래서 이미 왓슨을 보냈어요
So I already dispatched
Watson to her home
윌로우브룩 양로원으로
at Willowbrook Assisted Living.
더 부드럽게 진행되기를 바랄 뿐이죠
And, hopefully, that should
make things go more smoothly.
나가
- Get out.
- Ma'am.
-나가라고 했지
-사안회에 대해 말해야할
I said get out.
Ma'am, the reason I want to talk to you
이유가 있어서 그래요
about Snake Eye Triad...
안 되겠어요
Okay, that's
not very nice.
Look, three of your
husband's old gang members
남편의 조직 멤버 3명이
어젯밤 총에 맞아 사망했어요
were shot to death
the other night.
범인에게 정의를 실현하고싶지 않으세요?
Do you want that person
brought to justice or not?
받겠지
They will be.
멩 주는 하지 않아요
Your friend Meng Zhou
isn't so certain.
삼합회 일이 아니에요
This wasn't
Triad business.
범인은 백인이었어요
The killer was
a white man.
당신처럼 변장해서
세사람에게 접근했어요
He got close
to the three victims
by disguising
himself as you.
이걸 만들었어요
He made that.
할머니처럼 옷 입었고
He dressed like you.
Might not seem like much,
그다지 비슷해보이진 않지만
살해된 남자들을 속일 정도는 됐어요
but it was enough to fool
the men that were killed.
누구 짓인지 알죠?
You know who did it, don't you?
Two weeks ago, there was
a photographer here.
2주 전 사진사가 왔었어
백인
White man.
내가 윌로우브룩 신분증이 필요하다고 했어
He say I need
Willowbrook ID.
사진을 찍었지
He took pictures.
Then he want to know
about Snake Eye Boys.
그러더니 사안회에 대해 알고싶어했지
전에도 봤던 사람이었어요?
Had you seen him before?
아니, 화장실로 가서 프론트에
전화했지, 쫓아내라고
No. I go in bathroom to call
the front, ?Get him out.??
근데 돌아갔더니 없었어
But I come back, he left.
변태가 내 빨래를 훔쳐갔어
Pervert stole
my laundry.
옷을 가져갔어요?
He took your clothes?
저기 바구니에 있었지
It was in a
basket there.
내 자켓, 브라, 전부 다
My nice jacket,
bras, everything.
What did he look like?
어떻게 생긴 남자였어요?
White man, brown hair.
백인에 갈색머리였어
다른 건요?
Anything else?
몰라. 난 잘 안 보여
No, I don't see good anymore.
백인, 갈색머리
White man, brown hair.
관리자를 만나려고 기다리고 있어요
Still waiting to talk
to the administrator.
회의중이래요
He's wrapping
up a meeting.
타피오카 판매자와 치열한
협상 중이군요, 틀림없이
In the middle
of a heated negotiation
with a tapioca vendor, no doubt.
이 성의 왕이 되는 걸 상상해봤어요?
Can you imagine being
king of this castle?
여기서 사는 것보다 더 기분이 나쁜데요
I feel worse for the
residents who live here.
바이 메이룽조차도 이 가짜
자선단체에 사기를 당하고 있죠
Not even Bai May-Lung deserves
to be preyed on by
these faux charities.
How can you doubt
the authenticity
중학교에 탁구 테이블을 공급하는
of an organization
which has provided
기관의 진위를 어떻게
의심할 수 있어요?
at least one Ping-Pong table
to a middle school?
이민자 사회 어디든
Wherever there's
an immigrant community,
조폭의 주머니로 돈을 퍼넣는
there are these
neighborhood organizations
지역 기관들이 있죠
funneling cash
into gangsters' pockets.
차이나타운 지역 봉사단체는
You think the Chinatown
Community Outreach
삼합회가 만들었을까요?
is a Triad creation?
죽은 사람이 남긴 돈을 갈취하려고
속이는 거잖아요
They're trying to trick people
into leaving them money
when they die.
Hey there.
저기요
마이클 하스입니다
Hi. Michael Haas.
Michael Haas.
비서에게 듣기로는 저희 중에 살인자가
My assistant gave me the gist.
있다고 생각하신다면서요? 와우
Uh, you-you think we had a
killer in our midst, huh? Wow.
네, 와우
Yes, ?wow.??
범인이 보안카메라에 잡혔기를 바랐어요
We're hoping that
the culprit might appear
on your security footage.
복도에는 카메라가 없지만
Um, I notice you don't have
any cameras in this hallway,
입구에는 한 대 있던데
but the one
over by the front door,
충분하겠어요
that-that would be sufficient.
그게, 폐쇄회로라서
Actually, that's just
closed circuit.
It doesn't record.
녹화가 안돼요
밤에는 경비원이 있어요
At night, we have
a security guard at the desk.
들어오는 사람을 보고
문제가 없으면 들여보냅니다
He can see anyone who's coming,
buzz 'em in if it's all good.
그게 다입니다
But that's it.
살인자가 될 수도 있는
사람이 한낮에도 맘대로
So would-be murderers are only
free to roam the halls
복도를 어슬렁거리며
입주자를 괴롭히겠군요
and harass the residents
during business hours?
바이는 일하러 왔다고 주장하는
Ms. Bai said that her visitor
백인 남자가 왔었다고 했어요
was a white man
who claimed to work here.
파일을 보관하는 곳을 보여주실 수도 있겠죠
Maybe you could show us
where you keep your files.
직원기록이나 판매자 목록을
It would be helpful for us
보여주면 도움이 될 것 같아요
to look at employee records,
vendors with access.
보여드리고 싶죠
I wish I could.
당신이 보스 아닌가요?
You are the boss, right?
맞아요, 하지만 직원들에게는
사생활 보호의 권리가 있어요
Sure, but my people have
privacy rights.
영장 없이는, 힘들것 같아요
Without a... a warrant, uh,
I wouldn't feel comfortable.
하지만 상관없을 겁니다
But, listen, it doesn't matter.
그 사람은 여기서 일하지 않아요
This guy doesn't work here.
그건 지금 당장 말할 수 있어요
I can tell you
that right now.
왜죠?
How?
직원은 모두 25명입니다
We've got 25 people on staff.
절 빼고는
Except for me,
모두 자메이카인, 살바도르인, 중국인입니다
everybody's either Jamaican,
Salvadoran or Chinese.
백인은 없어요
No white men.
이걸로 대답이 되겠죠
Uh, that's just
the way it worked out.
We signed a visitor log
when we arrived.
들어올 때 방명록을 작성했어요
Is there anything else the
killer would have had to provide
입장허락을 받기 위해 범인이
제시해야했던 건 없나요?
in order to gain access?
Sorry, I mean,
Willowbrook is not a prison.
윌로우브룩은 교도소가 아니라서요
원하신다면 방명록 사본을 드리죠
But you can make a copy
of that log if you want.
Which dead gangster
do you want to start with?
사망한 조폭 중에 누구부터 시작할까요?
Uh, Adam Tsai.
아담 차이
첫발을 맞은 것 같아요
Looks like he might have
been the first one shot.
So who do you want,
Ray Mui or Gao Chung Pei?
누구 할래요?
레이 무이? 가오 청 페이?
동전 던져요
Flip a coin.
살인자의 신분을 알기 위해
Casting about
their criminal histories
피해자의 범죄경력부터 찾아보는 건
for clues of
the killer's identity
특정 범죄에 매우 매우
seems a very,
very broad approach
광범위한 접근이죠
for such a specific crime.
I don't see where else
we're gonna get traction.
끌리는 게 없는걸요
윌로우브룩의 방명록이 있지만
I mean, we have that copy
of the Willowbrook visitor log,
바이 메이룽을 만나러 가서
but it's not like the guy
would have signed in
본명을 썼을 리는 없잖아요
with his real name
to see Bai May-Lung.
Plus half those signatures
are illegible scribbles.
거기다 명단의 반은
읽기 힘들게 갈겨놨어요
솔레일의 모자상자는
어떻게 할 거예요?
What are you gonna do
with Soleil's hatbox over there?
내용물은 전혀 쓸모없어서
Its contents proved
to be entirely useless,
내일 아버지께 반납하려고요
so I'm returning it
to my father tomorrow.
He's in town?
뉴욕에 계세요?
Found out about what we did.
우리가 한 짓을 아셨어요
원래 있던 두 아들들보다
It would appear he's a much
more involved father
가져보지도 못한 딸에게
to the daughter he never had
더 부성애를 느끼시는 것 같아요
than he was to either
of the two sons he did.
도둑이 든 걸 알고 아버지께 연락했대요
Soleil called him after
she discovered the theft.
어제 날 찾아오셨어요
He came to see me yesterday.
That could not have gone well.
좋은 분위기는 아니었겠네요
He insisted Sabine Raoult died
because of him.
아버지 때문에 사비나가
죽었다고 주장하셨어요
He took full responsibility.
전적으로 자신의 책임이라면서
당신이 괴로워했을 말이네요
Sounds like that bothered you.
어머니 얘기 한 적 없었죠?
We never talked
about my mother, did we?
No, I mean, I know
she died a long time ago.
네, 오래전에 돌아가셨다는 것만 알아요
하지만 그 외에는
But other than that, I...
So, anything about me
나에 대해 당신이 아는
흥미롭거나 재밌거 좋은 점은
that you might find
interesting or amusing
or good,
you'd have found
a more pure distillation
'메이 홈즈'에게 더 정제된 상태로
발견할 수 있었을 거예요
of that in May Holmes.
8살 때, 아버지는 어머니와 이혼했어요
Naturally, my father divorced
her when I was eight years old.
I knew that trouble was brewing
마이크로프트와 내가
1년동안, 난 2년이었지만,
when Mycroft and I were
packed off to boarding school
기숙학교로 갈 예정이었을 때,
a year ahead of schedule--
two in my case.
문제가 심해졌다는 걸 알았어요
명절에 집에 돌아왔을 때
By the time we came home
for the holidays,
어머니는 쫓겨난 후였어요
my mother was out on her ear.
Your father threw her out?
아버님이 쫓아냈다고요?
어머니는 혼전 계약서를 작성했어요
Prior to marriage, she signed
a prenuptial agreement.
아버지가 모든 양육권을 가졌고
My father was guaranteed
full custody.
어머니는 방문권과
She was guaranteed visitation,
적은 금액의 생활비를 보장받았죠
a small amount
for living expenses.
이스트 엔드의 소박한
아파트에서 지내셨어요
She lived her last few months in
a modest flat in the East End.
소박하다는 말은 이웃의 보일러에서
So modest in fact that
it went up like a tinder box
불이 났을 때 불쏘시개가 된다는 뜻이죠
when the neighbor's
water heater caught fire.
Yeah, pretty sure the smoke
그래요, 아마 연기가 어머니를 덮쳐서..
would've got her
before the, uh...
그래서 그 이후로 2년동안
아버지와 말도 하지 않았어요
So I didn't speak to my father
for two years after that.
You held him responsible.
아버지 때문이라고 생각했군요
그랬죠
I did.
You still do.
지금도 그래요
I'm sorry.
유감이에요
Just give me one second.
잠깐만 시간을 줘요
Of course.
그럼요
난 지하에서 일해도 돼요
I can work downstairs.
Oh, no, I don't mean, um...
아니, 그런 뜻이 아니라
Here.
여기요
이걸 봐요
Have a look at this.
바이에게 손님이 있던 날 4번째 입구요
The fourth entry
on the morning Bai was visited.
봐요
Take a look.
What am I looking at? It looks
like a bunch of scribbles.
뭘 보라구요? 낙서 밖에 없구만
말하지 않았기 때문에
Just because it
doesn't say anything,
알려주지 않는다는 뜻은 아니에요
it doesn't mean
it doesn't tell us anything.
뛰어난 필적학자는 한낱 끄적거림으로
An elite graphologist
can use a mere doodle
샘플의 기본으로 삼아요
as the basis for a sample
in some instances,
그러니 뛰어난 필적학자가 되어봐요
so be an elite graphologist.
Okay.
알았어요
If this is the killer,
이게 범인의 글씨라면
왼손잡이라고 말할 수 있어요
I would say
he was left-handed.
비스듬하게 적혀있어요
Writes with a slanted baseline.
Yes.
맞아요
곡선을 봐요
Note the loops.
They might be arrhythmic.
불규칙적이에요
맞아요
They are.
여기서 봤던 것처럼
Just like the ones you see here.
Sven Eklund.
스벤 에클런드
The Good Samaritan
who called in the mugging.
강도사건의 착한 사마리아인이잖아요
강도사건에 연루된 작은 백인남성
The short white man
who committed the mugging.
Wrote down his contact details
for the police.
경찰에 넘길 연락처를 적어요
장의사네요
He's a mortician.
Hmm.
윌로우브룩 양로원에
Who does frequent business
with Willowbrook
Assisted Living.
자주 드나들죠
Their Family Resources page
calls his work
가족자원 페이지에서
'놀랍도록 실물과 같다'고 했어요
?incredibly lifelike.??
장의사의 접착제 기술 덕분이겠죠
Thanks to his skill
with mortician's putty,
틀림없이
no doubt.
팀 리더, 여기는 유닛 4입니다
Team leader, this is Unit Four.
근처에서 목격자는 없다고 합니다
Neighbors haven't
seen our guy either.
사업용 자동차에 대해 들은 얘기는 없습니까?
You got any word from the cars
that rolled on his business?
비어있었어
Place was empty.
이 블록 끝에 세워진 ND 자동차에 대해 보고하라
Listen, I want an ND car posted
at the end of this block.
남자는 도망쳤지만
This guy split, but...
you never know.
모르지
정신차릴 수도 있어
Maybe he'll come to his senses.
알겠습니다
Copy that.
What do you got?
뭘 찾았나?
The guy's missing
4개의 이중탄피 총알을 두고 갔어요
four double-aught shells.
오락실에서 사용된 것과 같은 총알입니다
It's the same kind
used at the arcade.
I take it this is
where he made the mask.
여기서 가면을 만들었나보군
여러개의 가면이
Masks, plural.
이걸 보세요
You need to see this.
Now, I recognize Bai and Meng.
바이와 멩은 알겠는데
다른 사람은 누군지 모르겠어요
No idea on the other guy.
나도 모르겠는데
Me neither.
그럼 이 사람들로 변장했을 수도 있어
So, he could look like
any of these people.
그럴 생각으로 보입니다
Seems to be the idea.
여러 피부톤을 만들 페인트가
There's paint on this table
탁자 위에 있어요
in a few different
flesh tones.
Pretty sure he made
masks of all of them.
전부 만든 게 분명해요
What the hell is this guy up to?
뭘 하려는걸까?
모르겠어요
No clue.
하지만 아직 살인이 끝나지
않았을지도 모릅니다
But he may not be
finished killing people.
You slept.
잤네요
네, 나도 인간이니까요
Yes, I'm human.
주기적인 수면이 필요해요
It is required periodically.
전화 소리에 깼어요
Your phone woke me up.
It was Marcus.
마커스였어요
스벤 에클런드의 부인이
선불폰에서 문자를 받았대요
Sven Eklund's wife
got a text from a burner phone.
"정말 미안해, 내일 떠나
?So sorry.
Leaving tomorrow.
안전할 때 연락할게"
I will call you when I'm safe.??
추격이 진행중인데
So, a manhunt's underway
도망가기 전에 시내에
and he's gonna spend
하루를 더 머물겠다니
a day in the city
before he flees?
국외로 탈출할 방법이 잘못됐거나
Could be he's scrambling for a
way to get out of the country.
Or he hasn't finished
what he's doing.
할일이 아직 끝나지 않아서?
아내는 남편이 삼합회 3명을
Did his wife
happen to know
살해한 이유를 알기는 해요?
why he rained hell down
on three Triad members?
No.
아뇨
하지만 최근 말기 진단을 받은 것 같아요
But apparently he got
a terminal diagnosis recently.
Cardiomyopathy.
심근병증이요
심장이 너무 커져서
His heart's gonna be too big
1년을 넘기기 힘들다고 했대요
to continue beating
within a year.
She thinks he snapped.
남편이 절망했다고 생각해요
자신의 죽음을 받아들이지
못하는 장의사라니
A mortician who can't come to
terms with his own mortality?
Eh.
바이의 가면은
Bai's mask was used
삼합회 멤버들에게 접근해서
to get close to and execute
살해하기 위해 사용됐어요
three gang members.
그리고 폐기됐죠
And then discarded.
멩의 가면은 사안회에 대한
A Meng mask would
suggest a fixation
집착으로 만들었을 거예요
with the Snake Eye Boys.
아마도 더 많은 살인을 위해
Perhaps he intends to use it
to commit more murders.
사용하려고 했겠죠
이 사람은 삼합회
조직원 같지는 않아요
This man doesn't look like
he's a member of any Triad.
No, but maybe Sven
used a mask
네, 하지만 스벤이
바이 메이룽을 만나러
윌로우브룩에 가려고
가면을 썼을 수도 있어요
to get into Willowbrook
to talk to Bai-May Lung.
눈이 잘 안 보이면
I suppose if you are half-blind,
이 사람이 백인으로 보이나보군요
this man might appear Caucasian.
멩 주가 경찰서에 왔대요
The captain's got Meng Zhou
coming into the station.
위험하다고 경고해야겠어요
We're gonna warn him
that he might be in danger.
윌로우브룩에 가서
Maybe you could
go to Willowbrook,
그 사람에 대해 내가 맞는지 알아봐요
see if I'm right
about that guy.
No.
아니야
옷을 가져간 사람이 아니라는 걸
You're quite sure
that's not the man
꽤 확신하시네요
who took your clothes?
댁도 눈이 멀었나?
Are you going blind, too?
This man is not white.
백인이 아니잖아
What about this man?
이 사람은요?
Maybe.
아마도
Maybe his cousin.
사촌일 수도 있어
The man who took my picture.
내 사진을 찍었던 남자는
코가 컸어
He had a big nose.
코를 빼면, 이 사람이 맞아요?
So him, except for the nose?
That's what I said.
내 말이 바로 그거야
We have no idea
what this man is planning,
이 사람의 계획은 모르지만
저희와 협력한다면
계획을 알아내서
but we can figure it out
and stop him
막을 수 있어요
if you work with us.
Three of your men
부하 3명이 죽었죠
have already died.
For all we know,
more attacks could be coming.
저희가 알기로는
공격이 더 있을 수 있어요
You really don't
want to tell us
에클런드가 사안회와 어떻게
how Mr. Eklund is connected
to the Snake Eye Boys?
연결됐는지 말하지 않을건가요
Never have I seen
this man before.
난 이 사람을 본 적이 없소
But this man.
하지만 이 사람
This is Terry Perez.
테리 페레즈요
And who's that?
누구죠?
He fixes machines
at the arcade for many years.
오락실 기계를 수리해주던 사람이지
But last week
he did something very unusual.
하지만 지난주에 무척
이상한 일을 했었어
Ray Mui, my friend--
레이 무이, 내 친구가
one of the men who died.
이번에 죽은 녀석 중 하나인데
He said that Terry came over
very late one night.
테리가 밤 늦게 가게에 왔다고 하더군
He-he looked strange.
이상하게 보였대
His face.
얼굴이
Uh, they thought
maybe he on drugs.
약을 했나보다 생각했대
He said nothing.
아무 말이 없었고
He just wave at
them to open up.
열어달라는 손짓만 했다더군
그 때가 새벽 1시쯤이었다지
But it was 1:00 a.m.
in the morning, huh?
그래서 내 부하가 "안돼,
So my friend said, ?No, no.
내일 와"라고 했다는군
You come back tomorrow.??
So Terry leaves.
그래서 테리는 갔다고 했어
Next day they call him
and-and he said,
다음날 전화해보니
?You mistaken.
"잘못 봤다
I was not there last night.??
난 어제 가지 않았다"라고 했다는군
Must've been Sven.
스벤이 틀림없어요
When his Terry mask
didn't work,
테리의 가면이 먹히지 않으니까
he made one
that looked like Bai.
바이의 가면을 만들었어요
I told you everything I know.
내가 아는 건 다 말했소
Now, you find this man.
이제 당신들이 찾을 차례요
If Sven really did have to take
two passes at that arcade,
스벤이 오락실에 2번이나
들어가려고 했다면
I guess your partner is right.
네 파트너가 옳다고 생각해
There's no such thing
as a master of disguise.
변장의 달인은 아니었어
At least we now know
what those two masks were for.
적어도 가면 2개의 목적이
뭔지는 알게 됐어요
멩의 가면이 남았네요
That just leaves us the one
that looks like Meng.
What's up?
뭐야?
셜록 말로는 바이를 만나러 갔을 때
Sherlock says that Sven
did not wear a mask
when he went to see Bai.
스벤은 가면을 쓰지 않았다고 해요
Just made his nose
a little bigger.
단지 코만 크게 만들었대요
하지만 또다시 "작은 것을 크게"
But just in case
Sven is going for
만들수도 있으니까
the ?less is more??approach
again,
수배사진에 여러가지 변장을
Sherlock mocked up
a few alternate looks
만드는 게 좋겠다고 해요
for the Finest Message
you issued.
Okay, I'll get these
out to our people.
그래. 이 사진을 보내지
아드님이 오셨습니다
Sir, your son is here.
예정에는 없습니다만
He's not on the schedule.
Send him in.
들여보내게
Yes, sir.
네
Sabine's things.
사비나의 유품입니다
아버지의 사랑하는 양딸에게
제 사과와 함께 돌려주세요
You can return them to your
beloved step-acquaintance
with my apologies.
사비나의 혐의는 없어졌어?
So, you've cleared Sabine?
아버지에 대한 사비나의
마음은 진심이라는
There's ample evidence
in her letters
충분한 증거가 편지에 있었어요
that her affection
for you is genuine.
하지만 어느쪽인지 방향을
결정하지는 못했어요
But there's nothing dispositive
one way or the other.
Only because you can't
prove a negative.
반대를 증명하지 못했기 때문이겠지
I could come much closer
if I could have access
사비나의 주요 이메일
계정에 접속할 수 있다면
to her professional
e-mail accounts.
더 가까워질 수 있을 겁니다
아버지의 파리 사무실에서
일했다는 거 알아요
I know she ran
your Paris office.
A review of her business
correspondence should settle it.
업무용 서신을 살펴보면 해결돼요
And when you've finished,
끝내면
come back and apologize.
돌아와서 사과해
That will be a cold day, indeed.
힘든 날이 되겠네요
It's uncanny.
묘하구나
When I look at you,
I see your mother.
널 보니 네 엄마가 보여
I hear her voice.
그녀의 목소리가 들려
I am my mother's son.
어머니의 아들이니까요
You have more in common
than you realize.
네가 아는 것보다 더 많이 닮았어
What's that?
뭐죠?
Something I dug
up last night
지난 번 대화 이후로
어젯밤에 뭘 찾았단다
after our little talk.
Records of her stay
at the Lawford Center.
로포드 센터 입원 기록이지
Did you really believe you're
the first addict in the family?
네가 가족 중에 첫번째
중독자라고 생각했니?
She had a problem.
네 엄마에게는 문제가 있었어
I didn't understand it.
난 이해하지 못했어
I only knew that
I loved her and...
내가 사랑하는 것만 알았고
결혼의 전제조건으로
and so I forced her to get help
도움을 받을 것을 강요했지
as a precondition
of our marriage.
It worked.
효과가 있었어
We started our family.
우린 가족이 됐어
Mycroft came along.
마이크로프트가 태어났고
And then you.
네가 태어났지
재활에 문제가 생겼을 때
When her sobriety
was finally punctured,
I sent the two of you
away to boarding school.
너희 둘을 기숙학교에 보냈
I urged her to return
to Lawford, she refused.
로포드로 돌아가라고
권유했지만, 거부했어
She thought she could
get well herself.
혼자서 극복할 수 있다고 생각했지
I told her it was a mistake.
그건 실수라고 말했지
Never have I been
so unhappy to be correct.
바로잡기 위해 그렇게
힘들었던 적은 없었어
She begged me not to tell you.
너희들에게는 말하지 말라고 부탁했었다
And for decades, I obliged.
수십년동안, 하지 않았어
하지만 더이상은 안되겠어
But no longer.
돕기 위해 헤어지자고 말했어야했지만,
I wish I could say
that I cut her off
to help her, but I can't.
지금은 아니다
Enforcing
our prenuptial agreement
혼전 계약서의 강요가
내 인생 가장 속좁은 짓이었지
was the pettiest thing
I've ever done in my life.
I made the decision
out of anger.
홧김에 내린 결정이었어
내 자신을 절대 용서할 수가 없다
And I shall
never forgive myself.
But enough is enough.
하지만 이만하면 됐어
Well, you don't get
to decide that.
결정을 못하셨군요
결정했다, 셜록
I do, Sherlock.
I have.
이미 했어
Now get out.
이제 나가거라
Sherlock, I don't know
셜록, 문자 답장이 없는
이유는 모르겠지만
why you're not returning
my texts,
스벤 에클런드가 아직 잡히지 않았고
but Sven Eklund
is still out there,
당신 도움이 필요해요
and we could use your help.
그러니 전화줘요
So call me back.
If that was Sherlock,
you can tell him to relax.
셜록이라면, 안심하라고 전해
스벤을 잡았어
We got Sven.
교통안보국 경찰이 JFK 공항에서
TSA and Port Authority Police
가짜 신분증을 낸 스벤을 잡았어
popped him at JFK
with a fake ID.
가짜 코에 갈색 가발을 쓰고 있었대
He had a putty nose
and a brown wig on.
우리가 보내준 변장 사진과 일치했다는군
Dead ringer for one of
the alternate looks we put up.
지금 데려오고 있어
They're bringing him
in right now.
Yeah, that's right.
맞아
The last one,
he-he started to run
마지막에 오락실 안쪽으로 도망가길래
to the back of the arcade,
알다시피, 내가 쫓아갔어
so I... you know,
I ran after him.
그녀석이 넘어졌고
난 가슴에 총을 쐈지
And he slipped and
I shot him in the chest.
Then I left.
그리고 나갔어
All right, just so we've
got the rest of it clear:
좋아요, 나머진 우리도 알아요
차로 가던 중
You were almost to your car
케빈 창이 다가와서
and then Kevin Chang,
he came up to you
지갑을 요구했지?
and demanded
your wallet?
아니, 내 지갑,
Well, no, my purse, actually,
그래, 그 때는 할머니였으니까
because, you know,
I was an old woman.
그 사람을 너무 많이 때렸나 싶었지만
I-I did feel a little bad
about how much I hit that guy,
아드레날린이 솟구쳐서 말이지
but there was
so much adrenaline.
스스로 정말 즐기는 것 같군
You seem awfully pleased
with yourself.
이유를 알고 싶은데
I'd like to know why.
이 일들을 벌인 이유가 뭐야?
What was all this about?
Wh...
There's three fewer
bad guys in the world.
세상에 나쁜놈 셋이 줄었잖소
I'm sure you appreciate that.
고마워할 줄 알았지
What were you gonna do
멩 주처럼 분장하고
뭘 하려고 했었지?
with the other disguise
that looked like Meng Zhou?
무슨 목적으로 쓰려고 했어?
What were you gonna use it for?
오락실에 들어가기 위해서
To get into
the arcade.
하지만 그녀석들이 매일
But then, you know, I realized
멩 주를 만난다는 걸 깨달았지
that those guys
saw him every day.
그 가면으로는 속일 수 없을테니까
The mask wouldn't fool them,
다른 걸 만들었어
so I made others.
못 믿겠어
I don't believe you.
스벤, 솔직히 말해봐
Come on, Sven,
don't get shy now.
우리가 당신을 찾는 걸 알았던 순간
I want to know
why you didn't run
도망가지 않았던 이유를 알고싶어
the second you found out
we were looking for you.
하루를 기다렸어
You waited a day.
다른 가면을 쓰려고
기다렸던 건 아니겠지
You sure you didn't stick around
to use that other mask?
당신 이름을 올린 다른 시체가 또 있나?
We gonna find any more bodies
with your name on 'em?
아니, 아니, 틀렸어
No, no, you've got
the wrong idea.
그럼 이해하도록 말해봐
Then help us to understand.
왜 그랬지?
Why did you do this?
팔에 있는 흉터는 왜 생겼죠?
Does it have something to do
with that scar on your arm?
얼마 안된 것 같은데
Looks pretty fresh.
한 3주 됐나
Maybe a few weeks old.
일하다 다쳤었지
I hurt myself at work.
방부처리를 할 때
We use surgical scissors
수술용 가위를 쓰지
when we do embalming.
뭘 떼어내려다가
갑자기 꺾였지
I-I-I left some out,
I just turned right into them.
나한테는 칼로 인한
상처 같아보이는데
Looks more like
a knife wound to me.
오락실에서 죽은 남자 중
You know, one of the men
at the arcade
레이 무이는
who was killed, Ray Mui,
죽었을 때 잭나이프를 휘둘렀지
he had a switchblade
on him when he died.
그것과 비슷한 상처를 남길거야
It would've left
a mark like that.
레이가 한 짓이지
He did that to you,
아니야?
didn't he?
오락실에서 복수를 끝내려고 했어?
So did you finish
getting your revenge
at the arcade,
아니면 더 저지르려고 했나?
or was there more?
Uh...
난 더이상 할 말이 없어
I-I don't have
anything else to say.
You got a year to live
목숨이 1년 남았다던데
거기 앉아서 3명을 살해한 방법을
and you were proud
to sit there and tell us
every detail about
how you killed three guys.
자세하게 자랑해보지 그래
이유를 말하지 않는 이유는
So the only reason
I can imagine
내가 보기에는 다른 일이 있기
때문이라고 생각하거든
you're not telling us why
is because there's
something you did.
Something you don't
want us to know about.
우리가 알지 않았으면 하는 게 있지
Get me a lawyer
변호사를 불러줘
아님 감옥에 보내든지
or take me to jail.
I'm done talking.
난 할 말 없어
I hope that second bag of
chips is a little reward.
2번째 봉지가 작은 보상이 되길 바라지
오늘 잘했어
You did good work today.
전 "불완전"으로 점수를 줬어
I'm giving myself an "I??
for "Incomplete??
I hear you.
이해해
스벤 에클런드를 잡았을 때, 그 3명 말고도
I'm pretty sure when Sven Eklund
goes to meet his maker,
더 살인을 저지르려 했다는 대답을 기대했지
he's gonna have to answer for
more than those three murders.
But...
하지만
-내일은 내일이야
-가시기 전에
tomorrow's another day.
Before you go...
제가 맞았어요
I was right.
스벤은 지난달 23일에 찔렸어요
Sven was stabbed
on the 23rd of last month.
해밀턴 병원 응급실에서 치료를 받았어요
He was treated in the ER
at Hamilton Hospital.
당시 의사도 수술가위
이야기를 받아들이지 않았어요
The doctors there weren't buying
his scalpel story, either.
이중날에 상처를 입었거든요
The blade that cut him
was double-edged.
So they filled out
a police report.
그래서 경찰 신고서를 작성했어요
That definitely
could've been made
레이 무이의 잭나이프로
인한 상처가 확실하군
by a switchblade like Ray Mui's.
더 빨리 알아내야했지만
We would've caught it sooner,
스벤이 신고하지 않아서
but Sven wasn't gonna talk
or press charges,
신고서는 서류더미 밑에 깔려있었어요
so the report got lost
on the bottom of the pile.
14번서에 갈 생각을 어떻게 했지?
How did you think to go
to the 14th Precinct?
They cover Hamilton
해밀턴 병원과ㅏ
영안실에서 가장 가까운 곳이죠
and it's the closest place
to the mortuary.
You think Snake Eye Boys
사안회가 영안실에서 공격했다고 생각해?
attacked him at his work?
Look at the intake time.
접수시간을 보세요
오전 11시30분
11:30 a.m.
We've got Sven's
work calendar.
스벤의 일정 기록이 있는데
아침에는 방부처리를 했고
He was doing an embalming
in the morning
12시에 고인과의 대면을 준비했어요
and he was supposed to handle
a viewing at noon.
삼합회가 영안실로 쳐들어가
Why would a Triad
charge into a mortuary,
두목이 누군지도 모르는
사람을 찌르는 이유가 뭘까?
stab somebody their boss
doesn't even know?
That's what I'd like to know.
제가 알아낸 것 같아요
살아있네요
He lives.
네, 연락 못해서 미안해요
Yeah. Sorry I've been
out of touch.
생각할 일이 있어서요
Had a few things to chew on.
가족 문제
Family matters.
You okay?
Yeah.
-괜찮아요?
-네
일에 집중하는 게 더 좋겠어요
I'll be better with some work
to focus on.
당신이 보냈던 ..
So I understand from your...
많은 메세지로 알고 있어요,
스벤은 만족할만한
many messages that Sven Eklund
has not confessed
자백을 하지 않았고, 다사다난했던
to anyone's satisfaction
and that you believe
사안회에 의해 칼에 찔렸다고 본다
he was once knifed by various
and sundry Snake Eye Boys.
하지만 스벤이 인정하지 않으면
어쩔 도리가 없어요
But he won't admit it,
which makes no sense.
동기도 모르고 물어보면
Couldn't confess fast enough
자백이 제때 나오지 않겠죠
until we asked him
about his motive.
복수로는 충분하지 않다?
Revenge was not enough?
복수에 대해 의문은 없어요
Well, there's no question
he got revenge,
근데 왜 우쭐해하지 않죠?
so why not crow about it?
삼합회가 자신의 일터에 들어와서
He didn't seem
to want to explain
먼저 공격했다는 설명을
why a Triad would
go into his business
하고싶지 않은 것 같았어요
and attack him
in the first place.
That's interesting.
흥미롭군요
Mmm.
그래서 이거요
So is this.
스벤이 그날 아침 처리하던 시체는
So the body that Sven was
working on that morning...
브렌트 아리에타였어요
Brent Arrieta.
He had been a resident
at Willowbrook.
윌로우브룩 입주자였죠
스벤의 손님 중 많은 수가
그 음산한 창고에서 나오겠군요
I imagine many of Sven's clients
come from that grim warehouse.
Yes, but it's strange.
네, 하지만 이상해요
방부 처리는 2시간정도 걸리잖아요
The embalming process takes
a couple of hours, right?
According to these
phone records,
이 통화기록에 따르면
스벤은 아리에타 시신을 작업하던 중
Sven took a break in the middle
of working on Arrieta
윌로우브룩의 소장,
마이클 하스에게 통화를 했어요
to call Michael Haas, the
administrator at Willowbrook.
2시간 후 스벤은 응급실로 갔죠
Two hours later,
Sven is in the ER.
There's something there,
I just can't place it.
분명 뭐가 있는데, 얘기를 못하겠어요
Course you can't.
못하죠
그 날 아침일찍 윌로우브룩에
'Cause you weren't with me
나랑 같이 있지 않았으니까
at Willowbrook
earlier this morning.
당신 기분을 상하게 했던 차이나타운
지역 봉사단체 포스터는 제거됐어요
The Chinatown Community
Outreach posters
which so offended you
have been removed,
하스 소장이 요구했겠죠
presumably at the request
of Mr. Haas.
하지만 확실히 알기 위해
아리에타의 시신을 파내야겠어요
But we'll have to exhume Mr.
Arrieta's body to know for sure.
Okay.
N-Now you really
have to tell me.
이제 말해요
Why am I here?
왜 내가 여기있는 거죠?
왜 아리에타씨를 보여주는 겁니까?
Why-why are you making
me look at Mr. Arrieta?
왜냐면
Because...
보여줘야했으니까요
we had to.
적절한 마음을 먹는 데 도움이
될 거라고 생각했어요
And we thought
it might help put you
in the proper
frame of mind.
지독한 냄새인 줄 알지만
I know it's dreadful,
스벤 에클런드가 방부처리를 하지 않았다면
but the stench
would be much worse
악취는 더 심했을겁니다
if Sven Eklund
hadn't embalmed the body.
스벤이 방부처리를 하다가
What we wanted
to talk to you about
멈추고 당신에게 전화를 한 이유와
was why he stopped
midway through that process
to call you
2시간 후, 해밀턴 병원에서
and why,
just two hours later,
팔을 봉합해야했던 이유를
he's getting his arm stitched up
들어보고 싶어요
at Hamilton Hospital.
바로 그 다음날,
And why, the very next day,
삼합회에 총을 쏘기 위해
도움이 될 사람들의
he started
photographing faces
사진을 찍으러 다니기
시작한 이유도요
that would help him shoot up
a Chinese Triad.
그 3가지가 연결되어 있다는 걸
Figuring out how
알아내는데 시간이 많이 걸렸어요
those three things connected
cost us a lot of sleep.
스벤이 전화를 한 이유는 알아요
You see, we now know why
Sven was calling you.
아리에타는 근이완제가 꽉 들어차있었죠
Mr. Arrieta here is still
chock-full of muscle relaxant.
-그게 사인이었어요
-주무시다가 돌아가셨어요
We know it was the cause of death.
He died in his sleep.
아니. 카리소프로돌 과다복용으로 사망했어요
No, he died of a massive
Carisoprodol overdose.
아마 음식에 섞여있어서
Probably administered
in his food.
숨을 쉬지 못하게 만들었겠죠
Made it impossible
for him to breathe.
안락의자에서 질식사했어요
Suffocated in his armchair.
스벤은 이 눈꺼풀 덮개를
넣으려다 알았을 거예요
Sven would've realized that
when he went to insert
these eyelid caps.
고인과의 대면에서
Morticians use them
눈을 뜨고있지 않도록
장의사들이 사용하죠
so the eyes don't open
during the viewing.
스벤은 아리에타의 동공이
확장되어 있는걸 봤어요
He would've seen Mr. Arrieta's
enlarged pupils.
근이완제 과도복용의
전형적인 징후 중 하나죠
You see, that is one of
the classic signs
of a muscle relaxant overdose.
Don't pretend this is the first
time you've heard this.
아니라고 하지 않는다는 건
처음 듣는 얘기라는 거
스벤은 발견한 걸 말하려고
당신에게 전화를 했어
Sven called you
to tell you what he'd found.
아리에타를 중독시킨 사람이
당신이라는 걸 모른채
Little did he know you were the
one who poisoned Mr. Arrieta.
아니야!
No!
내가 왜? 미쳤군
Why would I? That's crazy.
제일 먼저
Your first move
사안회에 전화를 했어요
was to call the Snake Eye Boys.
그들은 스벤을 찾아가
They went and ?explained??/i>
to Mr. Eklund--
레이 무이의 잭나이프의 도움을 받아
with the help
of Ray Mui's switchblade--
입을 다물어야한다고
'설득'했고, 통했어요
that he needed to keep
his mouth shut, which he did.
오, 그냥 살인자가 아니라
Oh, oh, so now I'm not
just the killer.
내가 삼합회를 부릴 수도 있는 사람이라고?
Now I can sic Chinese gangsters
on people?
할 수 있었어요
Sure, you could.
황금알을 낳는 거위니까
You were their golden goose.
포스터를 떼어내서
You gave yourself away
감추려고 했죠
when you took
the posters down.
차이나타운 지역 봉사센터
Chinatown Community Outreach.
세금감면 비영리단체 서류를 봤어요
We pulled the 501(c) paperwork.
스벤이 월요일 밤에 총격을 가한
That outfit was wholly owned
세사람의 소유였어요
by the three men
that Sven shot Monday night.
우리가 알아내지 못한 단 한가지는
About the only thing
we can't figure out
당신이 사안회를 위해서
일했던 이유였어요
is why you were scamming
for those guys.
우위에 서거나
쥐고 흔들수도 있었을텐데?
You get a cut, or did they
have something on you?
누구 말이오? 지금 누구
얘기를 하는지도 모르겠어요
What guys? I don't even know
who you are talking about now.
Ray Mui.
레이 무이
가오 청 페이, 아담 차이
Gao Chung Pei. Adam Tsai.
윌로우브룩 입주자들이 가짜 자선단체에
They had you pressuring
the residents at Willowbrook
기부하도록 당신에게 강요했지
to donate to their fake charity.
서류 추적은 생각 안했나?
You don't think
there's a paper trail?
어떤 자선단체에 누가 뭘 주든
난 관련이 없어요
I don't control who gives what
to what charity.
아니, 얘기만 하면 됐어요
No. You're just
a voice in their ear.
And anyone who makes
the mistake of listening
제대로 듣지 못하고
부동산을 넘긴 사람은
and revising their estate
gets a complimentary trip
스벤 에클런드에 의해
무료 여행을 떠나게 됐으니까
to Sven Eklund's slab.
여기서 볼 일은 끝났군
We're done here.
아닐걸
I don't think we are.
윌로우브룩의 최근 사망자들을
'Cause I'm pretty sure
that when we look at
살펴보니 확신이 들더군
all the recent deaths
at Willowbrook,
자선 기부 후 사망이라는
we're gonna find a pattern
패턴을 발견했어요
of charitable giving
and dirt naps.
나가면 안되겠소?
Can we please go outside? I...
여기서는 숨을 못 쉬겠어요
I can't breathe in here.
I...
I want immunity.
면책을 원해요
I can testify.
증언할 수 있어요
누구를 상대로?
Against who?
Those guys.
They have a boss.
그 사람들, 보스가 있잖아요
아, 그렇지, 멩 주
Yes, of course. Meng Zhou.
어젯밤 당신을 만나러 갔었지?
Came to see you last night,
didn't he?
How...
어떻게
당신들이 그걸 알지?
how did you know that?
멩 주는 오늘 아침일찍 경찰서에 왔었어
Meng Zhou was in our police
station earlier this morning.
윌로우브룩을 운영하던,
사망한 부하들의
He was pretty ticked
to find out about the scam
사기를 알고 무척 화가 났었어
his dead buddies had been
running at Willowbrook.
두목에게 말하지 않았나봐
Guess they never told him.
아냐
No.
했어
They did.
-알고 있었어
-그걸 당신이 어떻게 알지?
- He knew.
- How do you know?
당신을 찾아갔을 때 그렇게 말했나?
Did he say so when
he came to see you?
아무 말도 하지 않았어
He didn't say anything,
he just... handed me a note.
나한테 쪽지를 줬어
Something to
the effect of,
"멈추지마"라는 효과를 주는?
?Nothing stops??
Maybe a numbered account
자선단체를 대신할 번호 계좌?
that was supposed
to replace the charity?
If you had just asked
멩 주에게 질문을 했다면,
Meng Zhou a question,
just one,
한 번만 그의 목소리를 들었다면
you would've heard his voice
스벤 에클런드라는 걸 알았을텐데
and realized
it was Sven Eklund.
스벤은 심근병증이 있어
Sven has cardiomyopathy.
죽어가고 있지
He's dying.
He got stabbed
and he got angry.
칼에 찔렸고 화가 났어
And he wanted to provide
for his family.
그리고 가족을 부양하길 원했지
당신은 왜 사람들을 죽였지?
What's your excuse
for killing people?
Found something
in Sabine's e-mails.
사비나의 이메일에서 찾은 게 있어요
사비나의 운명이 감춰진 메세지
A message which sealed her fate.
And nearly yours.
아버지의 운명도
One of her old friends from
university was in town.
대학교 때부터 친구가
시내에 있었어요
밤에 한잔 하자고 했죠
Wanted to meet for a late drink.
Sabine told her where the two of
you would be dining that night.
사비나는 저녁에 아버지와
식사를 할 곳을 말해줬어요
즉석에서 내린 선택이었죠
There was no spur-
of-the-moment choice.
이미 결정됐었어요
She'd already decided.
항상 내게 원하는 걸
She always did have a way
얻어내는 방법을 알고 있었지
of getting
what she wanted from me.
사비나의 연루는 증명되지 않았어
It doesn't prove
she was complicit.
네, 사실은, 연루되지 않았어요
No. In fact, she wasn't.
사비나도 모르는 사이에
Unbeknownst to her,
이메일을 용병이 읽었어요
her e-mails were being read
by a mercenary.
I had a friend take a look
at her account.
사비나의 계정을 친구에게 보여줬어요
He discovered a worm
이메일을 몰래 복사해서
루슬란 크라스노프라는 남자의
which was blind-copying her mail
and sending it
to a separate account
별도 계정으로 보내는 웜을 발견했어요
belonging to a man named
Ruslan Krasnov.
Who is he?
누구지?
체첸 출신 청부업자요
A killer of Chechen extraction.
루슬란은 총을 쏜 사람일 뿐이죠
Obviously, Ruslan is just
a trigger man.
암살 시도의 설계자는 아니에요
He's not the architect of
the assassination attempt.
Should be easy enough
to find his employer.
고용인을 찾는 건 쉬워지겠지
그렇죠
It would be,
러시아 샹트페테르부르크 근처의
if he wasn't already serving
최고경계 교도소에서 이미
a life sentence
in a supermax prison
종신형을 선고받지 않았다면 말이죠
just outside
St. Petersburg in Russia.
소식통으로부터 대답을 듣고 싶다면
So if you want answers
from the horse's mouth...
방법을 찾으마
I'll find a way.
Did you
give me this
단지 겁을 주고 싶었어요?
just to be horrible?
Or... did you think
it would change anything?
아니면 뭔가 바뀌었으면 했나요?
도움이 됐어요
돌려드리죠
It is helpful.
I'll give you that.
제 자신의 문제에 대한
이해가 훨씬 늘었어요
It gives me
incrementally more insight
into my own problem.
She's no less dead.
죽은 사람이 돌아오는 것도 아니고
I'm no less an addict.
저도 중독자 그대로죠
And you're no more a father.
아버지는 예전 그대로가 아니에요
그게 어떤 건지 저도 알아요
I know what it's like.
To lose a great love.
위대한 사랑을 잃는 것
그게 아버지를 변하시켰고
It can change you,
나쁜 결정을 강요했어요
force you to make bad decisions.
I've told you.
말했잖니
If I could take back
the last 33 years...
33년 전으로 돌아갈 수 있다면
어머니 얘기 아니에요
I'm not talking about Mother.
아버지에겐 힘든 시간이죠
These are dangerous times
for you.
So I'd tread carefully.
그러니 신중하게 대할게요
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man